<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>talks on // Álex Go{,5z}</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/tags/talks/</link><description>Recent content in talks on // Álex Go{,5z}</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://agonzalezro.github.io/tags/talks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Closing 2016, a list of talks I gave</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/2016/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/2016/</guid><description>
Thanks @rais38 for the photo! We are almost at the end of January but I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to end the first month of the year without doing a small recap of the talks I gave last year.
When I moved to Spain at the end of 2015 I said to myself that I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to forget the little English I knew so I needed to force myself to keep traveling outside of Spain and to do some public speaking.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes volume plugins and Flocker</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/k8s_flocker_plugin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/k8s_flocker_plugin/</guid><description>
Last month I was working with the guys from Jetstack &amp;amp; ClusterHQ developing a plugina for Kubernetes that will allow the people to easily use Flocker there.
Yesterday I had the pleasure of sharing the stage with Rimas Mocevicius, Kelsey Hightower &amp;amp; Ivan Pedrazas at the Kubernetes London meetup to present the plugin and show the audience that creating volume plugins for Kubernetes is easier than it looks at the first glance.</description></item><item><title>How to deploy and update a python app using Kubernetes</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/oct_2015_djugl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/oct_2015_djugl/</guid><description>
Two days ago I gave a small talk in the DJUGL (Django User Group London) explaining how we could deploy a test application into Kubernetes. This post is going to explain something pretty similar, how to deploy a Flask app into Kubernetes and how to rolling update it.
Before starting, you can find all the materials of this post in my k8s-py-example repo.
Download the app and build it twice, one for each of the version that you want to deploy.</description></item><item><title>Go introduction at Shopa</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/go101/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/go101/</guid><description>
Here at Shopa we use Go for some services but we use a lot of Rails as well so not everybody needs to know Go. This is why I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to do a small introduction to it in one of our workshops.
The slides are mainly examples with a little bit of history around the Go world. If you find them useful, feel free to grab them here: https://github.com/agonzalezro/slides/tree/master/go
Probably I&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten about something but it was just a 1 hour and a half presentation.</description></item><item><title>Docker workshop at Shopa</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/docker_shopa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/docker_shopa/</guid><description>
Today I gave a workshop at Shopa about Docker: what is it, why it&amp;rsquo;s useful for us and why it can even be more useful.
I understand that just the slides without any context can be a little bit misleading, but in case that it helps somebody I will share them here:
The design of the PDF looks uglier than it really is, so if you want the html slides you can always use the Dockerfile provided with the source of the slides :)</description></item><item><title>The well deserved Golang UK conference is here</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/golanguk2015/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/golanguk2015/</guid><description>
Hi mum &amp;amp; dad (my 2 followers on the blog?) some friends, (Johanna, Sam &amp;amp; David) and myself have decided to organize a Go conference in the UK the next August 21.
He had opened the blind bird at the beginning of the week and we are already close to finish those cheap tickets, so hurry up and buy a ticket. We can see for the call for papers already received that the quality of the talks is going to be awesome, but don&amp;rsquo;t miss your opportunity as send us a paper before May 31st.</description></item><item><title>12 Go Best Practices</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/go_meetup_mar_2014/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/go_meetup_mar_2014/</guid><description>
Last Monday I had the chance to see @francesc talking on the Go London User Group. His talk was about best practices (and advices) when you are programming in Go.
Summarising it a little bit, I would say that some of the cases explained there are things that you are going to finish doing even without knowing that you are doing &amp;ldquo;best practices&amp;rdquo;, but they are other examples that are incredible useful and clever &amp;amp; I would love to assist to this conference few months ago.</description></item><item><title>Python and Scala smoke the peace pipe</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/pygrunn_2013/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/pygrunn_2013/</guid><description>
This was my talk on the PyGrunn conference last Friday.
I was explaining how can you communicate services written in different languages using Apache Thrift for that.
In few days the videos will be available, but TBH, I don&amp;rsquo;t really know if I will publish it here. It was not the first time that I talk in public using English, but it will be the first time that it is recorded&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t really know if I want to see that!</description></item><item><title>Here I go PyGrunn'13!</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/pre_pygrunn_2013/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/pre_pygrunn_2013/</guid><description>
I am really proud of say that the next month I will be giving a talk at PyGrunn!
This is a really good new for me because PyGrunn is the conference that my old colleagues organize since years ago. I was on it first time in 2011 just one week after I started working at Paylogic. I meet a lot of interesting people there and I will see them again this year!</description></item><item><title>PyGrunn Winter Hackathon 2012</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/winter-hackathon-2012/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/winter-hackathon-2012/</guid><description>
Few days ago, actually, more than one week ago (but I was very busy :) we made our first PyGrunn hackathon. I was lucky and from all the list of ideas, the selected was one of mines! The slides generator, that finally we call hovercraft. Here is a small introduction about what I wanted:
A small platform to create slides and have them always associated to a web with this possibilities:</description></item></channel></rss>