<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>talks on // Álex Go{,5z}</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/tags/talks/</link><description>Recent content in talks on // Álex Go{,5z}</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://agonzalezro.github.io/tags/talks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Closing 2016, a list of talks I gave</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/2016/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/2016/</guid><description>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="https://agonzalezro.github.io/rafa.jpg" alt="A cow" />
&lt;figcaption class="center" >Thanks @rais38 for the photo!&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>We are almost at the end of January but I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to end the first month of the year without doing a small recap of the talks I gave last year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I moved to Spain at the end of 2015 I said to myself that I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to forget the little English I knew so I needed to force myself to keep traveling outside of Spain and to do some public speaking. The public speaking bit is for two reason: keep forcing myself to speak English and&amp;hellip; to lose my fear about talking English in front of a bunch of people you don&amp;rsquo;t know about a tech that they probably know better than you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I could do it much better than I did, but I am happy with the results.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="my-english-talks">My English talks&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="custom-volume-plugins--kubeconhttpskubeconio">Custom Volume Plugins @ &lt;a href="https://kubecon.io">Kubecon&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=33VzHXuuRs4">Video&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href="https://speakerdeck.com/agonzalezro/custom-volume-plugins">slides&lt;/a>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I prepared this talk a lot, but I was pretty nervous on stage I did a terrible job. Some people said that they learn a lot of new concepts, but they were just trying to be friendly :) Probably I underestimated the pressure behind a Kubecon talk and I will fix this in the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="python-kubernetes-and-friends--pygrunnhttpwwwpygrunnorg">Python, Kubernetes and friends @ &lt;a href="http://www.pygrunn.org/">PyGrunn&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0tsaMVoydDg">Video&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href="https://speakerdeck.com/agonzalezro/python-kubernetes-and-friends">Slides&lt;/a>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I gave this in the best (IMHO, but I could be biased) Python conference in the Netherlands, it went pretty well, I knew the things I did pretty badly in my previous talk at Kubeconf and I tried to fix the problems. However, if you check the video and you can give me some advice, feel free.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="from-pets-to-cattle-the-way-of-kubernetes">From pets to cattle, the way of Kubernetes&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K_Kh4LMiiqQ">Video&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href="https://speakerdeck.com/agonzalezro/from-pets-to-cattle-the-way-of-kubernetes">Slides&lt;/a>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This talk was in Spain, but since it was a big conference I gave it in English for non-Spanish speakers. I think the talk was ok, I got a 4 out 5 in their feedback tool, but it seems I didn&amp;rsquo;t attach the people because nobody asking anything at the end. Out of camera I got several questions tho.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="and-the-spanish-ones">And the Spanish ones&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>All these talks were internal Jobandtalent talks for my ex-colleagues, I hope it helped them, they definitely helped me, it was a trusty environment and the questions were really interesting. You probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t ask that much in a conference but it helps the speaker (in this case me) to improve.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="go-101--jobandtalenthttpwwwjobandtalentcom">Go 101 @ &lt;a href="http://www.jobandtalent.com/">Jobandtalent&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zaywpuLV4BY">Video&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href="https://speakerdeck.com/agonzalezro/go-101-updated">Slides&lt;/a>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="kubernetes-101--jobandtalenthttpwwwjobandtalentcom">Kubernetes 101 @ &lt;a href="http://www.jobandtalent.com/">Jobandtalent&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5YmhMM_q4uI">Video&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href="https://speakerdeck.com/agonzalezro/kubernetes-101">Slides&lt;/a>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="docker-101--jobandtalenthttpwwwjobandtalentcom">Docker 101 @ &lt;a href="http://www.jobandtalent.com/">Jobandtalent&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;a href="https://speakerdeck.com/agonzalezro/docker-101">Slides&lt;/a>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Out of that list I gave some other, for example, about &lt;a href="https://github.com/agonzalezro/goqui/blob/master/examples/neo4j_intro_slides.neo4j">Neo4J&lt;/a> and a workshop with my friend &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ipedrazas">@ipedrazas&lt;/a> about Kubernetes &amp;amp; Docker, here, in Spain. Also, I started &lt;a href="https://meetup.com/mad-scalability">mad Scalability&lt;/a> and I am quite happy with about it!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will try to prepare some CFP in 2017, but as today I see it pretty difficult because of reasons :)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I said at the beginning of the post, one of the reasons why I tried to do public speaking is to improve at it, you if you have any advice &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/agonzalezro">share it with me&lt;/a> please!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kubernetes volume plugins and Flocker</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/k8s_flocker_plugin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/k8s_flocker_plugin/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Last month I was working with the guys from &lt;a href="http://www.jetstack.io/">Jetstack&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href="https://clusterhq.com/">ClusterHQ&lt;/a> developing a plugina for Kubernetes that will allow the people to easily use &lt;a href="https://clusterhq.com/flocker/introduction/">Flocker&lt;/a> there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yesterday I had the pleasure of sharing the stage with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Rimusz">Rimas Mocevicius&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/kelseyhightower">Kelsey Hightower&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ipedrazas">Ivan Pedrazas&lt;/a> at the &lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/Kubernetes-London/events/226026848/">Kubernetes London meetup&lt;/a> to present the plugin and show the audience that creating volume plugins for Kubernetes is easier than it looks at the first glance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an introduction of what you will find:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Introduction to Flocker&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Introduction to Kubernetes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Introduction to the plugin itself&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Code&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Summary&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Here they are:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Also, if you want to take a look to the presenter notes or the original slides, I have them in a GitHub repo: &lt;a href="https://github.com/agonzalezro/slides/tree/master/k8s_flocker_plugin">https://github.com/agonzalezro/slides/tree/master/k8s_flocker_plugin&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Feel free to contact me if you have any questions! I am &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/agoznalezro">agonzalezro in twitter&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to deploy and update a python app using Kubernetes</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/oct_2015_djugl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/oct_2015_djugl/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Two days ago I gave a small talk in the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DJUGL">DJUGL (Django User Group London)&lt;/a> explaining how we could deploy a test application into Kubernetes. This post is going to explain something pretty similar, how to deploy a Flask app into Kubernetes and how to rolling update it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before starting, you can find all the materials of this post in my &lt;a href="https://github.com/agonzalezro/k8s-py-example">k8s-py-example&lt;/a> repo.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Download the app and build it twice, one for each of the version that you want to deploy. This versions will need to be tagged properly and sent to &lt;a href="https://hub.docker.com/">Docker Hub&lt;/a>. Basically the steps to follow are:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>docker build -t agonzalezro/k8s-py-example .
docker tag agonzalezro/k8s-py-example:latest agonzalezro/k8s-py-example:0.1
# Change the code (src/app.py) a little bit to see the differences
docker build -t agonzalezro/k8s-py-example .
docker tag agonzalezro/k8s-py-example:latest agonzalezro/k8s/py-example:0.2
docker push agonzalezro/k8s-py-example
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Now that all the work related with Docker is done, let&amp;rsquo;s take a look to the needed k8s files:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>rc-0.1.yml&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>rc-0.2.yml&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&lt;strong>service.yml&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>The &lt;code>rc&lt;/code> files are the definitions of your replication controllers, one of them using the version &lt;code>0.1&lt;/code> and the other the image &lt;code>0.2&lt;/code>. The service file is share since the application is going to be the same.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s run the first version of the app:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>kubectl -f rc-0.1.yml -f service.yml --validate=false
# The validate tag is just needed because of a bug in current k8s
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Now, if you do &lt;code>kubectl get services&lt;/code> you will see the external IP of your service. You can use it to check that it&amp;rsquo;s running and showing the code of the version &lt;code>0.1&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cool! You have deployed your first k8s application, now, let&amp;rsquo;s update it:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>kubectl rolling-update flaskapp-rc -f rc-0.2.yml
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>If you wait a little bit you will see in the logs what&amp;rsquo;s happening there. Let the command finish and you will have your &lt;code>0.2&lt;/code> version deployed having causing 0 downtime!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As always, feel free to contact me here or use twitter: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/agonzalezro">@agonzalezro&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Go introduction at Shopa</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/go101/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/go101/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Here at &lt;a href="http://shopa.com">Shopa&lt;/a> we use Go for some services but we use a lot
of Rails as well so not everybody needs to know Go. This is why I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to
do a small introduction to it in one of our workshops.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The slides are mainly examples with a little bit of history around the Go
world. If you find them useful, feel free to grab them here:
&lt;a href="https://github.com/agonzalezro/slides/tree/master/go">https://github.com/agonzalezro/slides/tree/master/go&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Probably I&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten about something but it was just a 1 hour and a half presentation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://go-talks.appspot.com/github.com/agonzalezro/slides/go/101.slide">Here you can see them in
action&lt;/a>.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t iframed them here because the layout was ugly and the sliding between
slides kinda poor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/agonzalezro">Tweet me&lt;/a> if you have more comments!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docker workshop at Shopa</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/docker_shopa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/docker_shopa/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Today I gave a workshop at Shopa about Docker: what is it, why it&amp;rsquo;s useful for
us and why it can even be more useful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I understand that just the slides without any context can be a little bit
misleading, but in case that it helps somebody I will share them here:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>The design of the PDF looks uglier than it really is, so if you want the html
slides you can always use the &lt;a href="https://github.com/agonzalezro/slides/blob/master/docker/Dockerfile">&lt;code>Dockerfile&lt;/code> provided with the source of the
slides&lt;/a> :)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The well deserved Golang UK conference is here</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/golanguk2015/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/golanguk2015/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Hi mum &amp;amp; dad (my 2 followers on the blog?) some friends,
(&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/johannacherry">Johanna&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/_samdb">Sam&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/_samdb">David&lt;/a>) and
myself have decided to organize a Go conference in the UK the next August 21.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He had opened the blind bird at the beginning of the week and we are already
close to finish those cheap tickets, so hurry up and &lt;a href="http://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/golang-uk-conference-2015-tickets-16233380478">buy a
ticket&lt;/a>.
We can see for the call for papers already received that the quality of the
talks is going to be awesome, but don&amp;rsquo;t miss your opportunity as &lt;a href="http://www.golanguk.com/speakers/">send us a
paper&lt;/a> before May 31st.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a final note I want to and that if you want to sponsor the event or you have
any further question, feel free to presonally &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/agonzalezro">contact
me&lt;/a> or do it through the conference email:
&lt;a href="http://info@golanguk.com">info@golanguk.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I know that a bunch of assiduous people to the meetups is going already, so
hope to see you there as well!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>12 Go Best Practices</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/go_meetup_mar_2014/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/go_meetup_mar_2014/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Last Monday I had the chance to see &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/francesc">@francesc&lt;/a>
talking on the &lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/Go-London-User-Group">Go London User
Group&lt;/a>. His talk was about best
practices (and advices) when you are programming in Go.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Summarising it a little bit, I would say that some of the cases explained there
are things that you are going to finish doing even without knowing that you are
doing &amp;ldquo;best practices&amp;rdquo;, but they are other examples that are incredible useful
and clever &amp;amp; I would love to assist to this conference few months ago.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the beginning of the slides you are going to see an step-by-step refactoring
which could (and should) be applied to any other language out there. You will
realise of the major improvement on the readability of that piece of code.
Francesc said that the refactored version could possibly be a little bit
slower, but you will have in your power a piece of maintainable code.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I need to choose one of the tricks showed, I would definitely go for the
type switch on the (&lt;a href="http://talks.golang.org/2013/bestpractices.slide#8">slide
#8&lt;/a>). Basically, you can
receive an interface as parameter and do a quick casting to whatever kind of
type that you want:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>....
switch x := v.(type) { // where v is an interface{}
case string:
w.Write(int32(len(x)))
w.Write([]byte(x))
...
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>I would say too that coming from a language like Python, it&amp;rsquo;s really easy to be
temped to overuse that functionality :) What do you think?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, &lt;a href="http://talks.golang.org/2013/bestpractices.slide#1">here you have the
slides&lt;/a> enjoy them as I
did!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Python and Scala smoke the peace pipe</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/pygrunn_2013/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/pygrunn_2013/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This was my talk on the &lt;a href="http://pygrunn.nl">PyGrunn&lt;/a> conference last
Friday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was explaining how can you communicate services written in different
languages using &lt;a href="http://thrift.apache.org/">Apache Thrift&lt;/a> for that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In few days the videos will be available, but TBH, I don&amp;rsquo;t really know
if I will publish it here. It was not the first time that I talk in
public using English, but it will be the first time that it is
recorded&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t really know if I want to see that! :D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really need to improve my speed talking for the next time. I thought
that I will not have enough time to explain all, so, my subconscious
decided that I should be talking as a machine gun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Below, you will find the slides, if not, &lt;a href="https://speakerdeck.com/agonzalezro/python-and-scala-smoke-the-peace-pipe">try this
link&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>PS: you can find the source code of the slides here
&lt;a href="https://github.com/agonzalezro/slides/tree/master/thrift">[1]&lt;/a> &amp;amp; the
source code of the demo here
&lt;a href="https://github.com/agonzalezro/thriftest">[2]&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Enjoy them!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Here I go PyGrunn'13!</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/pre_pygrunn_2013/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/pre_pygrunn_2013/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I am really proud of say that the next month I will be giving a talk at
PyGrunn!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a really good new for me because PyGrunn is the conference that
my old colleagues organize since years ago. I was on it first time in
2011 just one week after I started working at
&lt;a href="http://paylogic.com">Paylogic&lt;/a>. I meet a lot of interesting people
there and I will see them again this year!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In 2012 I repeat, but at that time I had already started to organize the
&amp;ldquo;Monthly PyGrunn&amp;quot;s with &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/_ivor">Ivor&lt;/a>. TBH that talks
were quite successful, and not for the quantity of people that we get
there, if not for the quality of them and the networking after!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am really happy too because going there I will be able to see a lot of
friends that I miss! I just moved here 5 months ago but I really want to
see them!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, the less important thing: about the talk! I will be talking about
Thrift and how can we use it to talk between different applications in
different languages (in the examples: Python &amp;amp; Scala). When PyGrunn
finish I think that I will have a video where you can see the talk (or
check my English) and I will upload the slides too!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks to &lt;a href="http://www.pygrunn.org">PyGrunn&lt;/a> for give me this chance!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PyGrunn Winter Hackathon 2012</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/winter-hackathon-2012/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/winter-hackathon-2012/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Few days ago, actually, more than one week ago (but I was very busy :)
we made our first &lt;a href="http://paylogic.github.com/winter-hackathon/">PyGrunn
hackathon&lt;/a>. I was lucky
and from all the list of ideas, the selected was one of mines! The
slides generator, that finally we call &lt;strong>hovercraft&lt;/strong>. Here is a small
introduction about what I wanted:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>A small platform to create slides and have them always associated to a
web with this possibilities:&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Create an account with Google (or perhaps twitter, facebook&amp;hellip;), but Google seems the best option for me now.&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Create or edit new slides related with this account. This slides creator/editor will have the following functionalities:&lt;/em>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Select one image for background in fullscreen.&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Write one or 2 lines of text that will always fulfill the width of the slide.&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Change the font family.&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Have a permanent link to your slide (completely public for now).&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>After the hackathon we got something very similar to what I wanted, with
some small issues. But this post is not about what we did wrong! This
post is about which technologies did we use to finish the project and
perhaps, if I am lucky, start a discussion on why we did/didn&amp;rsquo;t make a
good choice.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-do-we-achieve-this">How do we achieve this?&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="backend">Backend&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The backend of the application was almost inexistent, we only wanted to
allow the users to login with a Google account to have access to edit
their slides. Being a hackathon we didn&amp;rsquo;t spend time adding CRUD
(Create/Read/Update/Delete) functionalities to manage the users.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to delete your user, let me know, I will do it by hand :) It
was made with &lt;a href="http://flask.pocoo.org/">Flask&lt;/a>, Flask-OAuth for the
authentication with Google and &lt;a href="http://redis.io/">redis&lt;/a> to store the
presentations.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="frontend">Frontend&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The viewer was really simply too because from the beginning we wanted to
play with the editor (it was more funny). For doing it we used
&lt;a href="http://lab.hakim.se/reveal-js/#/">revealjs&lt;/a> to show the presentation
with slide effect and &lt;a href="http://fittextjs.com/">jquery-fittext&lt;/a> to make it
fullslide.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now the important part! We made the editor with &lt;a href="http://agonzalezro.github.com/backbonejs-underscore-small-intro.html">backbone and
underscore&lt;/a>,
it seems to us the better choice, since we will have 3 principal views:&lt;/p>
&lt;dl>
&lt;dt>The background chooser&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>which is connection to &lt;a href="http://www.deviantart.com/">deviantart&lt;/a> to
perform a query of good backgrounds for your slide. Then you can
click on one of the results and will be applied to the current
slide.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>The font chooser&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>which is loading some google fonts, we wanted to do this
automagically but we couldn&amp;rsquo;t finish it at time. The behaviour is
the same, you choose a font and its applied to the current slide.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>The slide content&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>that should be WYSIWYG (What You See Is What You Get) but for now is
on the middle, because we couldn&amp;rsquo;t make the text bigger while you
are writing.&lt;/dd>
&lt;/dl>
&lt;h3 id="deployment">Deployment&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>And finally the deployment that was made with heroku and redistogo that
allows you to use a 5M non-persistant DB that is good for a demo.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="resources">Resources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>You can see the list of all the projects or&amp;hellip;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can find all the &lt;a href="https://github.com/agonzalezro/hovercraft">source on
github&lt;/a> or&amp;hellip;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can &lt;a href="http://nameless-spire-1402.herokuapp.com/">try a demo&lt;/a> too!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>And if you are too lazy to try it, here you have an screenshot:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://agonzalezro.github.io/hovercraft.png" alt="image">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="thanks">Thanks!&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I really want to thank &lt;a href="http://www.paylogic.nl">Paylogic&lt;/a> for letting us
a place where to do the project and for provide us food &amp;amp; beers. What a
developer will develop without food and beer?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I want to thank too all the guys that &amp;ldquo;spend&amp;rdquo; the weekend with me having
fun, but working hard too!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="conclusions">Conclusions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The good point of all this editing is that thanks to backbone and thanks
to the backend guys is saved without any action needed. The idea of this
full project was:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Have fun!&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Simplifying slide creation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make it really simply to share those slides.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to go really depth into the development of this project,
&lt;strong>I only wanted to give a quick overview of what we made in two days.&lt;/strong>
But if you are really interested on something more explained, let me
know on the comments and I will try to help you in all what I can.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>