<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>spacemacs on // Álex Go{,5z}</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/tags/spacemacs/</link><description>Recent content in spacemacs on // Álex Go{,5z}</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://agonzalezro.github.io/tags/spacemacs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Key bindings for Spacemacs</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/key_bindings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/key_bindings/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I am a happy user of &lt;a href="http://spacemacs.org/">Spacemacs&lt;/a> since few months ago. I was (and I still am) a vim user but Spacemacs provide you extremely good defaults and the installation of layers isn&amp;rsquo;t painful at all, things that I sadly can&amp;rsquo;t say about vim.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I ended up with a lot of configuration on &lt;a href="https://github.com/agonzalezro/.dot">my dot files&lt;/a> and everytime I wanted to try, for example, a new language, it was difficult to get it working well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, now that you know why I did the change let me show you the key bindings that I find useful:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Please, share yours with me! &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/agonzalezro">@agonzalezro&lt;/a> or leave a comment :)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PS: if you are starting in development I would start with Atom or some other editor. I moved from vim to Spacemacs because 1) I already knew some vim &amp;amp; 2) it works in terminal, and this is a must for me since I am a heavy user of tmux too.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Save hook for major modes</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/save-hook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/save-hook/</guid><description>
&lt;p>One of the things I like the most about Go is its &lt;code>go fmt&lt;/code> tool. I don&amp;rsquo;t worry about formatting my code while I am writing it because I know that &lt;code>fmt&lt;/code> is going to be there and it will do the work for me later.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Said that, the Go layer for Spacemacs is the one that is going to run it for you. Sometimes we need to deal with languages that don&amp;rsquo;t have this functionality, in my case, I found this issue working with Elixir &amp;amp; Ruby (happily Python forces you to write well :D).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since I got really used to the &lt;code>fmt&lt;/code> tool I wanted a similar solution for those languages and it seems that a simple auto indentation all over the file could do it for me. How did I add this behaviour for those languages? Just adding this to my &lt;a href="https://github.com/syl20bnr/spacemacs/blob/master/doc/DOCUMENTATION.org#alternative-setup">&lt;code>init.el&lt;/code>&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>(defun indent-some-languages()
(case major-mode
((elixir-mode ruby-mode) (spacemacs/indent-region-or-buffer))))
(defun dotspacemacs/user-config ()
...
(add-hook 'before-save-hook 'indent-some-languages)
)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>What I am doing there is registering a new hook just before saving the file that will check if I am in Ruby or Elixir mode and in that case call &lt;code>spacemacs/indent-region-or-buffer&lt;/code> that will indent the whole file for me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are familiarised with Lisp this snippet will probably look pretty simple to you; but trust me, it took me a while to make it work. This is the reason why I thought it could be interesting to share it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I would love to know your tricks for Spacemacs, share them with me here or at &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/agonzalezro">@agonzalezro&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>