<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>devops on // Álex Go{,5z}</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/tags/devops/</link><description>Recent content in devops on // Álex Go{,5z}</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://agonzalezro.github.io/tags/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to prepare the Certified Kubernetes Administrator exam</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/cka/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/cka/</guid><description>
Finally last weekend I did the CKA exam, I was procrastinating it a bit in part because I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what to expect since Kubernetes is huge and I thought that each day extra I spend reading about it would help me.
TLDR; I did pass the exam and if you work daily with Kubernetes or variants as Openshift you will be ok, they are not trying to catch you in some weird question that not even Kelsey would know how to answer 😀</description></item><item><title>Scheduling Your Kubernetes Pods With Elixir</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/elixir-scheduler/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/elixir-scheduler/</guid><description>
This was originally posted on deis.com.
Kelsey Hightower gave a really interesting talk at ContainerSched about how to create your own scheduler using the Kubernetes HTTP API.
The talk was awesome. It&amp;rsquo;s incredible to see what kind of things you can do with a base system as good as Kubernetes.
However, I missed one thing. The example provided by Kelsey was a Go application. Which is the main language used with Kubernetes.</description></item><item><title>Signing your GitHub work with your Keybase keys</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/keybase/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/keybase/</guid><description>
As you may know, yesterday, GitHub has presented a way to verify your commits on their platform. This is not something new, it&amp;rsquo;s part of the git protocol, but now, they will show a fancy &amp;ldquo;verified&amp;rdquo; label everytime you push a signed commit. Cool? Yeah, pretty cool.
One of the problems I always had since I know GPG is to keep my keys locally. I am pretty sure that some other people take care of their keys as if they were part of their family, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel that need yet.</description></item><item><title>Using Kong with Kubernetes</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/kong-k8s/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/kong-k8s/</guid><description>
This was originally posted on k8s.uk.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t know about Kong yet, you should take a look. It&amp;rsquo;s an Open Source API Gateway, they define themselves as: &amp;ldquo;The open-source management layer for APIs, delivering high performance and reliability.&amp;rdquo; and they are quite right.
I was playing with Kong lately at work (jobandtalent.com, we are hiring!) and I think that it could be pretty awesome as a entry layer to your microservices platform running in Kubernetes.</description></item><item><title>Log your Docker containers from a container with packetbeat</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/packetbeat-docker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/packetbeat-docker/</guid><description>
packetbeat is one of the best application performance management tools in the opensource community. It&amp;rsquo;s now part of the beats that Elastic provide us to monitor our applications. What it does is analyze our data packets to send some useful information to ElasticSearch.
After the introduction you probably realize that we will need: ElasticSearch installed and if you want to see something useful you will need Kibana as well. There is a guide for getting started that explains the process pretty clearly.</description></item><item><title>Dockerizing Pligg with Fig</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/pligg-docker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/pligg-docker/</guid><description>
For a pet project I needed Pligg which is kinda a social network site in the style of the old-digg (with karma and this kind of things).
Installing a LAMP system is kinda boring stuff, so, for that and for the sake of learning I decided to go with Docker &amp;amp; Fig. Sadly or luckily, every time that I dockerize something I find a lot of unexpected problems that slow me down, but&amp;hellip; you always learn something!</description></item><item><title>Tailing multiple logs with tmux</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/tailing-with-tmux/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/tailing-with-tmux/</guid><description>
I had a system that was creating a different log for each worker. Those logs where in the form: /var/log/baselog, /var/log/baselog.1, /var/log/baselog.2 and so on. I wanted to tail them but they were being updated simultaneously so the output of the tail was being a mess.
I am a tmux user since few months ago (if you aren&amp;rsquo;t, you should!) so I&amp;rsquo;ve decide to open all of them in different tmux panes.</description></item></channel></rss>