<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>environment on // Álex Go{,5z}</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/tags/environment/</link><description>Recent content in environment on // Álex Go{,5z}</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://agonzalezro.github.io/tags/environment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How I prepared my Mac to make some Docker development</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/docker-env/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/docker-env/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This post is about &lt;strong>how I did it!&lt;/strong> not about a standard way or something like
that, if you use any other way I would be happy to hear it on the comments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I usually use &lt;code>boot2docker&lt;/code> on my machine to run container, but it looks like
it was misbehaving a little bit when I was trying to create the binary of my
dev branch with:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ make binary
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Actually, it was just not creating it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I could also create some cross-compiled binaries but that didn&amp;rsquo;t work either.
It was a really weird situation because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find the path that it was
saying that it was creating. Not in my machine, not in my boot2docker VM
either. So, after some frustrating time I decided to go with vagrant.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-i-wanted">What I wanted?&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>My vim! I couldn&amp;rsquo;t live without that.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>My ssh keys for github and similar without copying them to the vagrant box.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="how-i-did-it">How I did it?&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="vagrant">vagrant&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>It was a simple process after you have clear what you really want to do:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ cd myawesomebox
$ vagrant init # Edit the file if you want more memory or similar
$ git clone git@github.com:YOUR_USERNAME/docker
$ vagrant ssh
$ sudo su -
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>What we did there? We have created a &lt;code>Vagrantfile&lt;/code> and we clone the repo in the
same folder. Thanks to that when we are inside the vagrant box (with &lt;code>vagrant ssh&lt;/code>) we will be able to access to it on the path &lt;code>/vagrant&lt;/code> of your box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The advantage of this approach is that you can access to all the docker code
from your host machine in the path &lt;code>myawesomebox&lt;/code> so you will not need to copy
any key, any conf or anything like that.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="docker">docker&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now it&amp;rsquo;s time to update your docker server and create your on docker client
(remember that we are logged in as root on that box):&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code># cd /vagrant/docker
# make build&amp;amp;&amp;amp;make binary
# service docker stop
# cp bundles/1.3.2-dev/binary/docker-1.3.2-dev /usr/bin/docker
# service docker start
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Where &lt;code>1.3.2&lt;/code> is the current version at the time of writing &amp;amp;
&lt;code>/usr/bin/docker&lt;/code> is your old docker server binary.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now you are running a new server, but where is the client?! Easy peasy, on the
same place that the server was originally:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code># bundles/1.3.2-dev/binary/docker
...
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>I usually alias it to the letter &lt;code>d&lt;/code> to access to it quicker without moving
stuff around:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code># alias d=&amp;quot;`pwd`/bundles/1.3.2-dev/binary/docker&amp;quot;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;h2 id="whats-next">What&amp;rsquo;s next?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I would say that develop some nice pull request? Or at least try! It&amp;rsquo;s fun
anyway :)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I went through all this pain while &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/eloycoto">@eloycoto&lt;/a> &amp;amp;
me were developing a &lt;a href="https://github.com/docker/docker/pull/9415">small PR to show vertical &lt;code>ps&lt;/code>
outputs&lt;/a>, so, thanks mate!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have any question or you think that my way of doing this stinks, please,
let me know! I would really, really appreciate it.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>