<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Álex's blog</title><link href="http://agonzalezro.github.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://agonzalezro.github.com/feeds/gnome.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://agonzalezro.github.com/</id><updated>2011-06-08T19:02:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>I'm starting to hate GNOME 3</title><link href="http://agonzalezro.github.com/im-starting-to-hate-gnome-3.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-06-08T19:02:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Álex</name></author><id>tag:agonzalezro.github.com,2011-06-08:im-starting-to-hate-gnome-3.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;First of all, I'm GNOME user as main desktop on Linux since the version
1.x (about 10 years ago). I've played with another desktops but GNOME
was always in my heart. But now, with the arrival of GNOME 3 and after
two weeks using it I can say that I'm starting to hate it. In this new
version it has a lot of functions that I don't like and doesn't have a
lot of functions that I like :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After see my arguments, perhaps you can help me to change my opinion but
possibily my next post will treat about how erase GNOME 3 and go back to
Unity. Go to see them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="fuuuu.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="fuuuu.jpg" class="align-center" src="fuuuu.jpg" style="width: 50%;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="dynamic-virtual-desktops"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Dynamic virtual desktops&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've always used virtual desktops. One for terminals, antoher for
explorers, another for music and a extra one for all other stuff. When I
want to go to my explorer I push Alt+2 and change my virtual desktop to
2. But now, I can't do it, because if I want to open the explorers in
the desktop 2 I must open something in the desktop one, but I don't like
it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a very big problem for me because I'm not accustomed to use
Alt-Tab to change the windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="when-you-close-the-las-window-in-a-desktop"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;When you close the las window in a desktop...&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the gnome-shell will be open! I don't like it! Perhpas I've closed this
window to go to my home folder, let me do that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="alt-f2-doesn-t-autocomplete"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Alt+F2 doesn't autocomplete&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GNOME always had this option instead KDE that didn't have it, and now,
they erase it? I can't understand why! I know that you can use the Super
key (the fuc***g windows key presented on all keyboards), but use the
gnome-shell to open a program isn't so quickly as open it with alt-f2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="autologin-on-gdm"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Autologin on GDM&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to suppose that this bug is only on my pc, because I've tried to
configure my autologin user and never ever is autologued. Perhaps I
should submit a bug for this case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="difficulty-to-install-extensions"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Difficulty to install extensions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will not say anything more about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="no-autohide-bar-and-no-more-bars"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;No autohide bar, and no more bars?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that gnome-shell isn't thinked to do that, but perhaps they must
give a chance to do that to the users that like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, one thing that happens with gnome-shell, gnome-do, meego
desktop... Why if you have hide files they appear on recent documents or
in the shell when you start to type? Of course... this hide files isn't
for p0rn, they are my personal documents only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="unity"></category><category term="gnome3"></category><category term="hate"></category></entry><entry><title>How-to install GNOME 3 instead of Unity on Ubuntu 11.04</title><link href="http://agonzalezro.github.com/how-to-install-gnome-3-instead-of-unity-on-ubuntu-1104.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-06-08T18:28:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Álex</name></author><id>tag:agonzalezro.github.com,2011-06-08:how-to-install-gnome-3-instead-of-unity-on-ubuntu-1104.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I don't have anything against Unity, but sometimes I want to test, and
this is one of this times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know the reason (or perhaps I do), but install GNOME 3 on a
ubuntu system isn't as easy as it must be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all we need to add the GNOME 3 repos, so, in a console (Alt+F2
and then write gnome-terminal) you must write:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
sudo add-apt-repository ppa:gnome3-team/gnome3
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, we must update our system and install the gnome shell:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
sudo apt-get updatesudo apt-get dist-upgradesudo apt-get install gnome-shell
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, sometimes we have problems with the themes (you can reboot
to test it, but I recommend you to follow this steps), so, we must
remove the accesibility themes and install the new ones (and another
program that we will need after that):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
sudo apt-get remove gnome-accessibility-themessudo apt-get install gnome-themes-standard gnome-tweak-tool
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well... now, you can reboot your system and login with GNOME selected as
session. You will see your new GNOME 3, but, we must tweak it, for this,
you can push Alt+F2 and write:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
gnome-tweak-tool
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recommend you to have this themes configuration (you can change the
icons if you like) and activate the option on the first tab called &amp;quot;Have
file manager handle the desktop&amp;quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="tweak_tool.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="tweak_tool.png" class="align-center" src="tweak_tool.png" style="width: 50%;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good luck! And if you have any trouble, please, feel free to ask me in
the comments!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://twitter.com/marioquartz"&gt;&amp;#64;marioquartz&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;wants to see the result, so here it is (click to
enlarge)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="gnome3_desktop.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="gnome3_desktop.png" class="align-center" src="gnome3_desktop.png" style="width: 50%;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
</summary><category term="unity"></category><category term="gnome3"></category><category term="desktop"></category><category term="ubuntu"></category><category term="gnome"></category></entry></feed>