<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>pygrunn on // Álex Go{,5z}</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/tags/pygrunn/</link><description>Recent content in pygrunn on // Álex Go{,5z}</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://agonzalezro.github.io/tags/pygrunn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Python and Scala smoke the peace pipe</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/pygrunn_2013/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/pygrunn_2013/</guid><description>
This was my talk on the PyGrunn conference last Friday.
I was explaining how can you communicate services written in different languages using Apache Thrift for that.
In few days the videos will be available, but TBH, I don&amp;rsquo;t really know if I will publish it here. It was not the first time that I talk in public using English, but it will be the first time that it is recorded&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t really know if I want to see that!</description></item><item><title>Here I go PyGrunn'13!</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/pre_pygrunn_2013/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/pre_pygrunn_2013/</guid><description>
I am really proud of say that the next month I will be giving a talk at PyGrunn!
This is a really good new for me because PyGrunn is the conference that my old colleagues organize since years ago. I was on it first time in 2011 just one week after I started working at Paylogic. I meet a lot of interesting people there and I will see them again this year!</description></item><item><title>PyGrunn Winter Hackathon 2012</title><link>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/winter-hackathon-2012/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://agonzalezro.github.io/posts/winter-hackathon-2012/</guid><description>
Few days ago, actually, more than one week ago (but I was very busy :) we made our first PyGrunn hackathon. I was lucky and from all the list of ideas, the selected was one of mines! The slides generator, that finally we call hovercraft. Here is a small introduction about what I wanted:
A small platform to create slides and have them always associated to a web with this possibilities:</description></item></channel></rss>